BEN KASONGO MUKEBO

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full-stack software developer with a background in engineering and 4+ years of industry experience. I specialize in React, Nextjs, Ruby on Rails, and React Native. A skilled mentor with the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of 10+ developers to build software programs and effectively track changes.

EXPERIENCE

FIDBA GRAPHICS, Remote, and Full-time

Front End Developer | February 2021 - May 2023

Designed +4 professional websites for African companies, which positively impacted their businesses by generating a 20% increase in online leads and doubling their online sales.

MICROVERSE, Remote, and Part-time

Code Reviewer | October 2021 - February 2024

- Complete 20+ weekly reviews for students from all over the world who are working on projects in CSS, ReactJS, and Ruby.
- Provide suggestions on maintaining app development best practices, professionalism, and compliance with QA guidelines.

NEUTRAL, Remote, and Part-time

Back End Developer | March 2022 - Present

- Designed and developed the Neutra platform from the ground up, utilizing cutting-edge technologies and optimized processes, resulting in a 14% increase in website loading speed to deliver a high-performing and scalable web development experience.
- Created custom APIs and optimized database performance for a smooth experience, resulting in 19% less page load time.

JUUBIX, Remote, and Internship

Full-stack / Sublead Backend Engineer | April 2023 - November 2023

- Propose improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance of the application.
- Build smart contracts with Rust package manager (Cargo)

VAURSE, Remote, and Full-time

Front End Developer | May 2023 - Present

- Contributing to the development of our highly anticipated first production set and launch in Ghana and the UAE in Match 2023.
- Collaborating with a dynamic team to create an exceptional user experience and set new industry standards.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE | June 2021 to March 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing apps.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard GitFlow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ULK KIGALI | September 2018 - December 2021 Bachelor of Electronics and Telecommunications,

Developed over 15 IOT-based projects that provided solutions to problems in medicine, agriculture, and automation.

Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn | Medium l.benkasmukebo7@gmail.com

Contact: +(250) 784 165 613

SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React JS, React Native, Redux, Zustand, React Query, Context API, SASS, Tailwind, Material-UI, Next UI, and Shadon.

Back-end: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Redis, ActiveAdmin, Administrate, Supabase.

Databases: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools: Git, GitHub, Docker Containers, Heroku, Figma, Postman, Rswag, ERD, RSpec, TDD, Capybara, Jest, React testing library, Chrome Dev Tools, Clickup.

Methodologies: Mobile/Responsive Development, Application Programming Interfaces, Product Integration, Test Automation, Microservices.

Professional: Mentoring, Remote Best Practices, Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Leadership, Analytical Thinking, and Verbal Communication.

PROJECTS

Sweet~aromas

- Recipes catalog that provides instructions for preparing and producing a certain food or drink. built with React, Redux, context, and Ruby on Rails
- Source code
- Live demo

Health-care-online-system

- System designed to help facilitate the acceptance of the medical treatment of people (workers and their dependents) if approved by the organization.
- Ruby on Rails (Administrate)
- Source code
- Live demo (In development)

Other private repo:

- KAWIRA SAFARIS LTD
- Ritach
- satec congo
- FELI Technology
- Hillwood Empire (In development)

LANGUAGES

English - Professional.

French - Native.